<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>prestia.org</title>
 <link href="http://prestia.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://prestia.org"/>
 <updated>2012-01-27T20:52:20-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://prestia.org</id>
 <author>
   <name>Anthony Prestia</name>
   <email>anthony@prestia.org</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>1955 - 2011</title>
   <link href="http://prestia.org/quotes/2011/10/05/1955---2011"/>
   <updated>2011-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://prestia.org/quotes/2011/10/05/1955---2011</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hero.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Steve Jobs, 1955-2011&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No one wants to die. Even people who want to go to heaven don’t want to die to get there. And yet death is the destination we all share. No one has ever escaped it. And that is as it should be, because Death is very likely the single best invention of Life. It is Life’s change agent. It clears out the old to make way for the new. Right now the new is you, but someday not too long from now, you will gradually become the old and be cleared away. Sorry to be so dramatic, but it is quite true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your time is limited, so don’t waste it living someone else’s life. Don’t be trapped by dogma — which is living with the results of other people’s thinking. Don’t let the noise of others’ opinions drown out your own inner voice. And most important, have the courage to follow your heart and intuition. They somehow already know what you truly want to become. Everything else is secondary.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;— &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UF8uR6Z6KLc&quot;&gt;Steve Jobs, 2005&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Back to Basics</title>
   <link href="http://prestia.org/sicp/2011/09/29/back-to-basics"/>
   <updated>2011-09-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://prestia.org/sicp/2011/09/29/back-to-basics</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Like a good number of nerds my age, my first experience writing code was copying BASIC programs from the back of old computer magaziness. Over time, I began experimenting with HTML and took a few C++ courses in high school. After a few Java classes in college, I gave up formal computer science training and just hacked around in my free time. I had a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of free time.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned quite a bit about writing software and maintaining a server over the years, but I could never shake the feeling that I missed &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; by not majoring in computer science. I was never really sure what that something was, but I felt that my purely pragmatic education left a sort of hole in my experience that CS students didn't have. As a result, I always felt like an outsider (if not an outright fraud) talking with CS-diploma-wielding &lt;em&gt;engineers&lt;/em&gt; at local tech and startup events. Still, I quickly learned that this feeling beat the alternative: Admitting that I'm an attorney.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I decided a few weeks ago that it is finally time to fill this hole. I did some asking around and bought a couple of books that appear to be widely regarded as the best for learning CS fundamentals: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0070004846/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=anthonypresti-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399369&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0070004846&quot;&gt;Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs&lt;/a&gt; [&lt;a href=&quot;http://mitpress.mit.edu/sicp/full-text/book/book.html&quot;&gt;free html version&lt;/a&gt;] and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0262033844/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=anthonypresti-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399369&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0262033844&quot;&gt;Introduction to Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;. I keep pretty busy with work and a few &lt;a href=&quot;http://teachprivacy.com&quot;&gt;outside projects&lt;/a&gt;, but I'm setting aside at least an hour each day to work through these books. I already started working through SICP and, despite Scheme's strange syntax&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I'm rather enjoying the book. The expository bits are good (if a bit dry) and the problem sets are challenging without being overly frustrating. I don't think this is a particularly great introduction to programming for someone who is casually interested in the subject&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but it is perfect for my purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to eventually post my answers to the problem sets on this website (they are currently occupying a spiral-bound notebook), but I haven't decided if I will post them to the main page or hack together multipage support in my blogging software. Look for them in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; How much free time? Enough to learn some Java, JavaScript, Python, Ruby, and a host of web-centric technologies.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;fn2&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Seriously, if you ever want a group of self-respecting hackers to ignore every word you say, just walk up to them and say you're an attorney. I'm pretty sure that, as a class, we are disliked even more than Pointy-haired Bosses and Douchebag Business Guys.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;fn3&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Or should I say Lisp's strange syntax?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;fn4&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; For softer introductions to programming, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://tryruby.org&quot;&gt;Try Ruby&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://learnpythonthehardway.org&quot;&gt;Learn Python the Hard Way&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://mislav.uniqpath.com/poignant-guide&quot;&gt;Why's (Poignant) Guide to Ruby&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codeschool.com/&quot;&gt;Code School&lt;/a&gt; also has some great learn-by-doing tutorials.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Gap.com is a Nightmare Waiting to Happen</title>
   <link href="http://prestia.org/writings/2011/08/14/gapcom-is-a-nightmare-waiting-to-happen"/>
   <updated>2011-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://prestia.org/writings/2011/08/14/gapcom-is-a-nightmare-waiting-to-happen</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I discovered today that the entire family of Gap websites (gap.com, bananarepublic.com, oldnavy.com, piperlime.com, and athleta.com) store customer passwords in plain text. This is particularly worrisome because these websites also store the customer's name, address, email, phone number, and credit card number. It is possible that the credit card numbers are properly hashed (I have no way to verify), but this still wouldn't prevent massive fraud if someone were to steal the customer database and post it online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you shop at any of these websites and have your personal data stored, now would be a great time to delete it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>dodo&#58; A Template for toto</title>
   <link href="http://prestia.org/projects/2011/08/10/dodo-a-template-for-toto"/>
   <updated>2011-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://prestia.org/projects/2011/08/10/dodo-a-template-for-toto</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;What is dodo?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dodo is a personal blogging template for the compact, hacker-friendly blog engine &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/cloudhead/toto&quot;&gt;toto&lt;/a&gt;. Dodo looks beautiful and degrades gracefully thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://html5boilerplate.com/&quot;&gt;HTML5 Boilerplate&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jquery.com/&quot;&gt;jQuery&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.modernizr.com/&quot;&gt;modernizr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/p/hyphenator/&quot;&gt;hyphenator.js&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://softwaremaniacs.org/soft/highlight/en/&quot;&gt;highlighter.js&lt;/a&gt;. All posts are written in &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/&quot;&gt;John Gruber&lt;/a&gt;'s excellent &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&quot;&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt; syntax and published to &lt;a href=&quot;http://heroku.com/&quot;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&quot;http://git-scm.com/&quot;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dodo was written by &lt;a href=&quot;http://anthonyprestia.com&quot;&gt;Anthony Prestia&lt;/a&gt; and you can see it in action on his (now retired) &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.anthonyprestia.com&quot;&gt;personal blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Want to try dodo?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming you are already a &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://heroku.com&quot;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt; user, setup takes less than 10 seconds:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git clone git://github.com/prestia/dodo.git &amp;lt;blog_name&amp;gt;
$ cd &amp;lt;blog_name&amp;gt;
$ heroku create &amp;lt;blog_name&amp;gt;
$ git push heroku master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once installed, you can configure dodo by modifying the &lt;code&gt;config.ru&lt;/code&gt; file. The default options are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;set :blog_title,   ''  # main blog title
set :author,       ''  # blog author
set :root,         &quot;index&quot;  # page to load on /
set :markdown,     :smart  # use markdown + smart-mode
set :disqus,       ''  # disqus id, or false
set :fulltext,     ''  # for index, true or false
set :summary,      :max =&amp;gt; 150, :delim =&amp;gt; /~/
set :ext,          'txt'  # file extension for articles
set :cache,        28800  # cache duration, in seconds

set :git,          false  # github username
set :twitter,      false  # twitter username
set :description,  ''  # default blog description
set :main_url,     ''  # main, non-blog url
set :analytics,    ''  # your site's Google Analytics ID

set :date,         lambda {|now| now.strftime(&quot;%B #{now.day.ordinal} %Y&quot;) } # date format for articles
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Problems?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dodo is a work in progress. While it is perfectly stable, some code is still a bit messy and there may be some layout hiccups. If you have any problems using &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/prestia/dodo&quot;&gt;dodo&lt;/a&gt;, please submit them &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/prestia/dodo/issues&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Horseman Arrives</title>
   <link href="http://prestia.org/opinions/2011/08/07/a-horseman-arrives"/>
   <updated>2011-08-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://prestia.org/opinions/2011/08/07/a-horseman-arrives</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I planned to write a long piece about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/z?d112:h.r.01981:&quot;&gt;Protecting Children from Internet Pornographers Act of 2011&lt;/a&gt;, but I waited a bit too long and Conor Friedersdorf at &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt; managed to nail pretty much everything I wanted to say. If you haven't done so, read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/politics/print/2011/08/the-legislation-that-could-kill-internet-privacy-for-good/242853/&quot;&gt;his article&lt;/a&gt; immediately. I'll wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of what Friedersdorf mentioned, I'll add only two things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I want to stress the seriousness of this bill. H.R. 1981 is the digital the equivalent of allowing a federal agent to follow you around taking excruciatingly detailed notes just in case someone one day thinks you may have done something illegal. This is absurd, creepy, and absolutely unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, I want to emphasize the importance of carefully scrutinizing any bill that claims to exclusively target one of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_Horsemen_of_the_Infocalypse&quot;&gt;Four Horsemen of the Infocalypse&lt;/a&gt; (terrorists, pedophiles, drug dealers, and money launderers). These four categories of criminals are so universally reviled that individuals are often quick to sacrifice individual liberties to combat them. These &quot;temporary&quot; sacrifices often end up lasting for decades and can be incredibly damaging.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Stupid iPhone Tricks</title>
   <link href="http://prestia.org/how-to/2011/07/20/stupid-iphone-tricks"/>
   <updated>2011-07-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://prestia.org/how-to/2011/07/20/stupid-iphone-tricks</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I picked up an iPhone just over a month ago and was surprised to see how many iOS features are completely unknown to even long-time users. I decided to publish a few of my favorites below. I tried to stick to lesser-known and/or undocumented features, but a few exceptions were made for features with great utility that could easily be overlooked. A number of additional tips are available on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/iphone/tips/&quot;&gt;Apple's website&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/recaptcha/mailhide/d?k=01FAJRu4IEah-HzAYVZTRecg==&amp;amp;c=fcbpT_qA3-yRrkBAuz9xC_Vh6XpgWTxxP6Wrpan1bzo=&quot;&gt;submit&lt;/a&gt; any tricks that I might have missed.
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Keyboard Tricks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Quick Top-Level Domains&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people are comfortable using the &quot;.com&quot; button when entering a URL into Safari. However, few realize that if you briefly hold down the &quot;.com&quot; button an extended list of top-level domains appears. This makes accessing your favorite .net, .edu, .org, and .us domains a snap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Special Characters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a friend with a pesky tilde in her name? Enjoy a good umlaut now and again? iOS has you covered!
Similar to the quick top-level domain trick, a handy menu pops up whenever you hold down a commonly &quot;accessorized&quot; character. Notably, this trick works for accented vowels as well as punctuation marks like the upsidedown questionmark and ellipsis. Play around and see what else you can find!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Quick Periods&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When typing, it is not necessary to end each sentence with a period. When you reach the end of a sence, simply hit the spacebar twice and iOS will automatically end the prior sentence with a period followed by a space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Quick Punctuation &amp;amp; Numerals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When inserting punctuation and numerals into your writing, you needn't hit the &quot;.?123&quot; button, select your character of choice, and switch back to the qwerty keyboard with the &quot;ABC&quot; button. Instead, you can simply hold the &quot;.?123&quot; button until the punctuation and numeral keys appear, slide over to the character of choice, and then lift your finger from the screen. Sure, it's still a three-step process, but it's only one button press and lightning quick!
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Multitasking Interface&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that amazes me is the number iPhone veterans that still don't realize that multitasking was introduced in iOS 4. To access this feature, simply double tap the home button and a multitasking interface is displayed at the bottom of the screen. Swipe the interface to the left to dig deeper into your history of recently used applications. Tap any app's icon to pick up where you left off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Quick Music Access and Music Control&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the first page of the multitasking interface (double tap the home button), swipe to the right instead of the left. Here you will find an icon to access whatever music app you last used (iPod, Pandora, Rdio, Spotify, etc.) as well as a few simple music controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Lock the Screen Orientation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the first page of the multitasking interface (double tap the home button), swipe to the right. In addition to the music controls and iPod icon, there is a grey icon on the left with a curved arrow. Tapping this icon will lock the orientation of the screen. This is particularly helpful for those that love reading sideways or upsidedown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Forcing an Application to Restart&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although iOS applications tend to be pretty stable, it's inevitable that a few bugs creep through the certification process and leave you with a non-responsive app. If this happens, simply exit the application by hitting the home button. Once out of the application, double click the home button to bring up the multitasking interface. Next, tap and hold any app icon in the multitasking interface until they all begin to wobble and display a red circle with a white - (minus) in the upper left corner. Unlike the traditional red circle with an x inside, tapping these symbols will not delete the app from your phone. Instead, these symbols simply force the application to stop running in the background. You can then reopen that application in the normal fashion and it should, hopefully, be working as normal. Notably, you can scroll through your extended history of applications to close apps that started malfunctioning long ago.
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Other Tricks &amp;amp; Hacks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of times when taking a picture of your iPhone's screen would come in handy. Fortunately, such a feature is integrated into iOS. Simply push the home button and power button simultaneously and the screen wil flash white signifying that a picture has been taken. You can later retrieve these photos from within the Photo app, just as you would a photo taken with the iPhone camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Fast Scrolling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many apps that require a substantial amount of scrolling, a simple tap of the status bar (the bar up top that displays time and battery information) will instantly scroll you back to the top of the document. This is especially useful in Mail, Safari, and a number of Twitter apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Advanced Music Control&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people don't realize that the default iPhone headset actually has a number of tricks tucked into the microphone. On any version of the iPhone headset (with or without volume controls), clicking the middle of the microphone yields the following results:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One click:&lt;/strong&gt; Pause or resume playing music or, if you have an incoming call, pause music and answer the call or hang up the call and resume music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two clicks:&lt;/strong&gt; Skip to the next track&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Three clicks:&lt;/strong&gt; Return to the previous track&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Emoticons/Emoji&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a warning, this is a bit more of a hack than a trick. Ever since the introduction of iOS 2.2, Apple has included a fairly large (and often strange) library of emoticons for use in SMS messages. Unfortunately, these emoticons are only officially available to Japanese iPhone users. To access the emoticons there are two common options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jailbreak your iPhone and modify a plist file; or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download one of the many &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/emoji-free/id332509635?mt=8&quot;&gt;free apps&lt;/a&gt; that grant access to the emoticons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>iPhone Users Are About to Be Screwed Over</title>
   <link href="http://prestia.org/opinions/2011/02/08/iphone-users-are-about-to-be-screwed-over"/>
   <updated>2011-02-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://prestia.org/opinions/2011/02/08/iphone-users-are-about-to-be-screwed-over</id>
   <content type="html">

&lt;p&gt;The next iPhone (presumably called the iPhone 5) is rumored to include a near field communication (&quot;NFC&quot;) chip that could be used for ExpressPay/PayPass-like credit card transactions. Last month, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2376702,00.asp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;John C. Dvorak declared&lt;/a&gt; this technology &quot;to be the most onerous ever.&quot; Dvorak apparently lives in some crazy world where &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/wiki/Nexus_S&quot;&gt;other phones&lt;/a&gt; don't already contain NFC chips and only Apple has ambitions of turning cell phones into &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/wiki/Mobile_payment#Contactless_Near_Field_Communication&quot;&gt;NFC-enabled credit cards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dvorak argues that NFC-enabled phones would be tremendously convenient, but that the costs of routing your payments through a mobile carrier are much too high. He states:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;If you think your banker is a gouger with dubious fees and no-leeway, what do you think the phone company will be like? Yes, let AT&amp;amp;T handle all your money for you, and see how that works out in the end.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I agree: Letting your phone company become entangled with your daily financial transactions is probably not a good idea. And, yes, I know that phone companies &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobilecrunch.com/2010/11/16/att-t-mobile-verizon-working-together-on-isis-nfc-mobile-wallet-system/&quot;&gt;would love to do this&lt;/a&gt;. But how does Dvorak logically jump from &quot;smartphones will enable mobile transactions via NFC&quot; to &quot;carriers will necessarily be involved with these transactions&quot; to &quot;iPhone users are screwed&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NFC has a maximum range of 20 centimeters and does not require a cellular connection to operate. There is no requirement that a wireless carrier ever become involved with an NFC transaction. Presumably, the most logical use of NFC would be for PayPal, American Express, Visa, etc. to build mobile applications that link to pre-existing financial accounts and are processed identically to current credit or debit transactions. In this situation, the only way the wireless carrier would become involved is if they started charging a toll to connect to your financial institution's servers (net neutrality, anyone?). Even if this practice were adopted, installing Wi-Fi connections near store registers would quickly alleviate the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the carrier-controlled application ecosystems of the past, your cellular service provider could ensure that all NFC transactions passed through their applications and show up directly on your monthly statement. Today, however, carriers are unable to limit what shows up in the App Store and Android Marketplace. Consider the numerous credit card processing applications available on both Android and iOS. Your wireless carrier is not taking a percentage from those transactions. NFC transactions are no different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that Dvorak is crying wolf. Of course, this is the same guy who predicted in 2007 that the iPhone would fail and is most famous for stating in 1984 that &quot;[t]he Macintosh uses an experimental pointing device called a &amp;lsquo;mouse&amp;rsquo;. There is no evidence that people want to use these things.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He's been wrong before.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Raising Hackers</title>
   <link href="http://prestia.org/opinions/2011/01/11/raising-hackers"/>
   <updated>2011-01-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://prestia.org/opinions/2011/01/11/raising-hackers</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was recently forwarded a few news articles about a growing number of high schools introducing iPads into their curriculum. The sender assumed that I would be excited about the idea, but was surprised to hear I had a number of reservations. My response, although long and a bit grandiose, was originally intended for a single-person audience, but has since been forwarded around to a number of people. So far, it has generated some positive discussion among high school faculty members and I thought I would reproduce it here to generate further discussion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've been reading about iPads in schools a lot lately and, honestly, I don't know how I feel about the idea. I think that computers and emerging technology should definitely have a place in the high school curriculum. However, I'm not convinced that the current iteration of technology facilitates or otherwise improves traditional methods of learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my own experience, I have found that a pen and a pad are far superior to a laptop (or an iPad) in a classroom environment. This is most likely true because I, like most anyone of my generation or younger, am much faster at typing notes than writing by them hand. Because the note-taking process is much slower by hand, I am forced to put more thought into what I actually write down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To illustrate my point:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a typical law school lecture, I could easily sit with a laptop and absent-mindedly transcribe every word spoken in the class. However, when using a pen and pad to take notes, I was forced to listen to the in-class discussion, synthesize the information, and then commit the most salient points to paper. The extra steps involved in the writing process, I think, are critical to developing a deep understanding of subject matter. Quickly typed notes may be comprehensive, but they are rarely ever considered more than superficially. At best, students give typed notes a re-reading come exam time and then never look at them again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second reservation about using iPads in the classroom is that they are primarily a closed system. iPads, like most modern technology, actively discourage tinkering. iPads work so intuitively that most owners use them every day without giving a single thought as to how they actually work. This is absolutely the wrong way for children to learn about technology. Computers are tools that can be used by anyone&amp;mdash;children and adults alike&amp;mdash;to drastically reshape every facet of the world around us. Consider the average smart phone. Not only has the smart phone largely replaced the landline, but also, through applications, it has replaced the alarm clock, the notepad, the point-and-shoot camera, the flashlight, the level, and a whole host of other devices. Individuals with the ability to write software are fundamentally changing the way the world works. We need to encourage students to become these individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we give students iPads for taking notes and running educational software, we reinforce the idea that they are consumer products. We show them how to use software, but not how to use the underlying hardware. By treating technology as nothing more than a consumer good, we forget that it is a tool and what we are capable of creating  with it. We look at the device with wonder instead of wondering how we can use the device to change the world. Without obtaining the  knowledge necessary to program our devices, we risk turning the computer&amp;mdash;one of the most powerful tools man has ever created&amp;mdash;into nothing more than an expensive television.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the forward-thinking schools introducing iPads are full of exceptionally bright and malleable minds. For this reason, I think the approach to introducing technology should be handled with heightened care. From what I have heard (and I could be mistaken), the interest in programming courses at many advanced high schools has  dwindled since I was in my teens. This is troubling. Introducing technology to the classroom is one of the most important things a school can do, but a strong programming curriculum must be in place first. If I were to introduce iPads into a school, I would attach the following requirement: Any student wishing to obtain an iPad for use in class must enroll in a relevant programming course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would be shocked if many students didn't accept that offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have little doubt that a current high school student could change the world with a great idea and a few lines of code; I just fear he or she will never realize he is capable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; The text above has been slightly modified from the original. The original email discussed a particular high school in the final two paragraphs, but I have changed it to be more general. Otherwise, the text is presented as originally written, warts and all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>